# RUSHIKESH MAHINDRAKAR

 $+91~8446039154 \diamond Pune$ , Maharashtra, India

mahindrakar.rushikesh93@gmail.com  $\diamond$  LinkedIn  $\diamond$  GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Backend Developer with over 7 years of experience in the information technology and services industry. Specializes in cloud platform services, particularly AWS, and excels in version control tools like Git. Experienced in agile methodologies and proficient in Microservices, C#, ASP.NET Core Web API, Node.js, Angular, AngularJS, and ASP.NET.

#### **SKILLS**

**Technical Skills** 

Programming Languages C#, Javascript

Backend Frameworks ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC, ASP.Net Core Web API, Node JS

Frontend Frameworks Angular and Angular JS

Databases MSSQL, MySql, MongoDb, Dynamo DB

Cloud Experience Microservices, AWS - EC2, Lambda Functions, API Gateway, S3, Step Functions

Other Tools Git, BitBucket, Jira

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Senior Software Engineer

July 2022 - Present Pune, Maharashtra

• Onboarded new client in invoicing report module and achieved 90% code coverage.

- $\bullet$  Engineered automation tool for QA team, developing scripts to retrieve executables from cloud source and installed on designated machines; streamlined process, cutting deployment time by 60% and improved accuracy of installations
- Wrote scripts for migrating the instances between AWS accounts, reducing manual effort by 60%

#### Senior Software Engineer

February 2021 - June 2022

HCL Technologies

Innova Solutions

Pune. Maharashtra

- Contributed in the implementation of the drag and drop feature in the scheduling module which demonstrated a performance level of 75% efficiency with up to 1000 data entries.
- Wrote lambda function which was able to shut down instances as per the tag defined, reducing the costs by over 35%.

## Software Engineer

March 2019 - February 2021

NeoSoft Technologies

Pune, Maharashtra

- Upgraded one of the Lambda function in Nodejs from a single file which contained 15000 lines to a Serverless Express Framework, with testable code and 95% code coverage.
- Optimized a lambda function, reducing execution time by 70% (from 10 mins to 3 mins) and lowering costs as a result.

#### Developer

October 2018 - March 2019

PT. Manggala Cipta

Jakarta, Indonesia(Remote)

- Developed blogs module with 100% code coverage.
- Onboarded a SSL vendor(5th vendor) and consumed the purchase and renew APIs

#### Developer

June 2016 - September 2018

Codevian Technologies Pvt Ltd.(Formerly-The Axontech)

Pune, Maharashtra

- Promoted as Team Lead for 3 projects and delivered those on time and within budget, utilizing diverse technologies
- Analyzed requirements, created milestones, and set realistic deadlines for 5 major projects and 10 minor projects.

## **PROJECTS**

## Pre-Pay Editing Tool

- Offered as one of the service of the portfolio, Pre-Pay Editing enables the clients to access and modify claim details with the support of Rule engine. The Rule engine can be configured differently for every client.
- Technologies and Tools: Net Core, Net Core Web API, AWS Lambda, AWS Step Functions, AWS S3, AWS API Gateway, AWS SSM Documents, GitLab, Python, Powershell

## Scheduling Management Tool

- Scheduling Management Tool falls under Advanced Planning and Scheduling Portfolio. The tool creates production schedules based on availability of resources, constraints and materials required by the order.
- Technologies and Tools: .Net Core, .Net Core Web API, TFS, ReactJS, AngularJS

## Dental Insurance Billing Software

- This software provides comprehensive dental billing services, managing insurance claim processing, submissions, follow-ups, appeals, and revenue optimization, allowing in-office staff to focus on patient care. Their remote dental billing teams ensure accurate charges, claim submissions, and daily reconciliation for efficient insurance management.
- Technologies and Tools: ASP .Net MVC 4, NodeJs, GitHub, ReactJS, AngularJS, AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS Code Pipeline, AWS Amplify, AWS S3, AWS Cloudwatch, AWS SQS, AWS SNS

#### EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- At "Codevian Technologies", in order to address intranet-based source code system, I conducted informative sessions introducing Git, emphasizing the need for transition and explaining fundamental commands.
- Presented a training session on CORS in .NET Core, covering CORS configuration in code and Azure App Service which had 70% team attendance.

# **LEADERSHIP**

 Pioneered leadership of a cross-functional team developing Dental Insurance Billing Software, overseeing projects in .Net, NodeJs, Angular, ReactJS, and Flutter; drove team efficiency, resulting in a 25% faster project completion time

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Application, Pune University Bachelor of Computer Application, Pune University August 2014 - June 2016 June 2011 - March 2014